Komlan ZANKPE

DevOps Engineer

Critical thinking DevOps Engineer with background designing, testing and **implementing infrastructure** and applications. Talented performer with over **6 years** of experience using source control tools to **identify and fix bugs in code**. At Orange Business Services, I have developed my architecture skills and I was introduced to Hybrid cloud with **Azure Arc**.

Work History

2021-06 - present

DevOps Engineer

Thales Services Numeriques, Velizy (FRANCE)

Company specialized in the design, development and maintenance of secure Information Systems

Orange Bussines Services, within the Azure practice:

- Collaborated closely with projet teams and other stakeholders to deliver projects.
- Contributed to the design and implementation of the Landing Zone with Terraform
- Implemented hybrid cloud architecture with Azure Arc
- Migrated workload to Azure using Azure Services Recovery
- On premises infrastructure assessment with Azure Migrate

2018-11 - 2021-07

Cloud Devops Engineer

Neocase Software, La Garenne Colombes (FRANCE)

A leading provider of integrated HR and Finance service delivery solutions At the core of Cloud and Security team, leading the automation work to cut down delivery time:

- · Migrated applications to Azure (Lift and Shift)
- · Automated deployment with Powershell scripts
- ARM templates and DSC used to build Infrastructure as Code
- · Monitored client's application with ELK stack
- Developed custom PowerShell module for application administration
- Analytical thinking to resolve critical issues encountered in production

2016-06

- 2018-10

Technical Implementation Manager

Ariane Systems, Pantin (FRANCE)

A company providing online check-in/out technologies to the hotel industry. Within the project team and collaborating with the development team:

- PaaS management: deployment and management of azure resources
- Deploy client environments using webservices
- Advanced technical support on the applications
- · Wrote training documentation and guidelines

2014-02 - 2016-03

Field Service Engineer

Arelis Group, Colombes (FRANCE)

Specialized in design and integration of electronic solutions

Working with the 2nd Authority for Television and Radio (Jerusalem). Broadcasting DVBT and DVBT2 signal in Israel:

- Installation and maintenance of RF transmitters
- · Network monitoring
- Storage and resources management
- Ensure client's expectations were satisfied

Personal Info

Email

kzankpe@gmail.com

Phone

+33(0)695294930

Skype

kzankpe

Address

66 rue d'estienne d'orves 93110 Rosny sous bois

FRANCE

GitHub

kzankpe

Soft Skills

Agile Methodology

Critical Thinking

Teamwork

Continuous Improvement

Positive Attitude

Technical Skills

Cloud Management (Azure)

Configuration Management

CI/CD (Azure Devops)

Version Control Software (Git)

ARM Template/Bicep

Terraform

Powershell

Python

Windows server

IIS

MS SQL Server

Docker

Unix/Linux

Golang

Hashicorp Vault

Education

2009-09 - 2012-09 **Telecommunication Engineering, Master's Degree**

Institut Supérieur d'Electronique de Paris, FRANCE

Classes: Signal processing, Wireless networks, Electronics, Digital communications, Web development ...

Certificates

Az-104: Microsoft Azure Administrator

Az-400: Designing and Implementing Microsoft DevOps

Solutions

AZ-305: Designing Microsoft Azure Infrastructure Solutions

Projects

2021-10

Python Django

- present

Developping applications with Django Framework and Bulma CSS.

Languages

French



English